# Sergio Penagos Developer

Highly motivated and result-oriented developer with over five years of experience collaborating with international and national teams to build visually, aesthetic, responsive and accessible websites. Effective problem solving skills, outstanding interpersonal skills, excellent in written and verbal communication. Ability to work independently as well as within a team environment.

WORK EXPERIENCE

### Vass, Remote — V2 Developer

Aug 2021 - Jan 2024

Collaborate with international teams (product managers, designers, and backend engineers) to execute functionality of designs.

Help to build a few web apps to manage all aspects of compliance for bank companies, using Vue.js, TypeScript, Javascript, Styled Components, Storybook and other libraries/tools.

Expand functionality with documentation that improved project comprehension by 30%.

## Dolphin Ingeniería S.A.S, Remote — Web Developer

Mar 2021 - Jun 2021

Work closely with other team members on the development team.

Translate design team's UX wireframes and mockups into responsive, interactive features, using HTML/CSS and TypeScript.

Help develop new features, do bug fixes and code maintenance in general for the Kairos web application using Front end technologies.

Improve bug reduction by 20% through code refactoring.

## Qoopa S.A.S, Remote — Web Developer

Dec 2019 - Mar 2021

Create new components and upgrade existing ones for the company's custom UI library using React Native, Vue js and Styled Components.

Build interactive websites, apps and online systems using Javascript, Typescript, HTML and CSS, LARAVEL.

Optimize performance thanks to reduced Css and Javascript sizes using TypeScript and a css preprocessor , so improved load times by 40%.

## Soulmedical, Bogotá — Web Developer

Apr 2019 - Nov 2019

Solve bugs and implement new features on the website.

Develop web pages using HTML, bootstrap 4, JavaScript, Jquery, PHP and added asynchronous features using AJAX.

sergiopenagos881@gmail.com (57) 3229206546 Linkedin profile Github profile Work github profile Portfolio

#### FRONT-END SKILLS

Html5

Css

Bootstrap [4,5], Bulma, Materialize

JavaScript,

Vue (Vuex, Pinia, Vue-Router)

React

**React Native** 

**TypeScript** 

Eslint, Prettier

i18n

Stylelint

#### **OTHER**

Github, Bitbucket

**Figma** 

Jira, Trello

Scrum

Slack

#### **LANGUAGES**

**Conversational English** 

## Conex Travel, Bogotá — Web Developer

Oct 2017 - Dec 2018

Develop a responsive user interface for a web application with front-end technologies HTML, Css (bootstrap) , Javascript(React js ) and back-end technologies Php

Optimize React projects to reduce file sizes and improve load times by 20%.

Create reusable components to share across projects and reduce redundant code.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Universidad Internacional de La Rioja, Bogotá — Informatics Engineering

Current

Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje, Bogotá — Associate's Degree Technologist Analysis of Information Systems

Apr 2020 - Jul 2022

Servicio Nacional de Aprendizaje, Bogotá — Associate's Degree Technical Software Developer

Oct 2018 - Nov 2019